Koji Tominaga

Centre for Ecological and Evolutionary Synthesis (CEES)
Department of Biosciences, University of Oslo
P.O. Box 1066 Blindern • 0316 Oslo • Norway
koji.tominaga@ibv.uio.no

Summary

I am an environmental scientist with a specialisation in scientific high-performance computing. My application fields to date have been **climate change**, **anthropogenic pollution**, **biogeochemistry**, and **freshwater systems**. My interests in computing and numerical methods include **machine learning**, **parameter estimation**, **quantification of modelling uncertainty** and **data visualisation**. Highlights in HPC experiences:

- Environmental model implementation on 3 HPC platforms (Notur/Norstore, Sharcnet, Amazon EC2),
- · Management of terabyte data arrays, and
- Expert skills in **Unix**, **Python** and **R** languages.

Education

2009–2013	PhD in Biology, University of Oslo
2007–2009	MSc in Environmental Science, Trent University
2003–2007	BSc in Environmental Science, Trent University

Academic Exchanges

Feb-Mar 2009	Technische Universität München
Apr–Jun 2009	Norwegian Institute for Water Research

Work Experiences

2013–current	Post-doctoral researcher, University of Oslo
2010–2013	Part-time Researcher, Norwegian Institute for Water Research
2006–2009	Research Assistant, Trent University
2007 – 2008	Teaching Assistant, Trent University
2008	Seminar Instructor, Trent University
2006–2007	Grader, Trent University
2006-2007	Technical Assistant, Kawartha World Issues Centre

Relevant Communications

- [1] Couture RM, Tominaga K, Starrfelt J, Moe SJ, Kaste Ø, et al. (2014) Modelling phosphorus loading and algal blooms in a nordic agricultural catchment-lake system under changing land-use and climate. Environ Sci: Processes Impacts 16: 1588–1599.
- [2] Tominaga K (2013) Lake Modelling: an interdisciplinary context. PhD thesis, University of Oslo, Oslo, Norway.
- [3] Tominaga K, Finstad AG, Kaste Ø, Andersen T (2012) Future climate change impact on lakes in fennoscandia: A dynamic mechanistic approach. Otsu, Shiga, Japan. 2012 ASLO Aquatic Sciences Meeting. Oral presentation. Presenter.
- [4] Tominaga K, Aherne J, Watmough SA, Alveteg M, Cosby BJ, et al. (2010) Predicting acidification recovery at the hubbard brook experimental forest, new hampshire: Evaluation of four models. Environ Sci Technol 44: 9003–9009.
- [5] Tominaga K, Aherne J, Watmough S, Alveteg M, Cosby B, et al. (2009) Voyage without constellation: evaluating the performance of three uncalibrated process-oriented models. Hydrol Res 40: 261–272.

In total, I have 6 peer-reviewed publications showcasing the uses of HPC methods, approximately 30 conference abstracts, 4 times peer-reviewer contributions, and attended numerous international scientific meetings in 13 countries.